like to introduce our guest today dr.
face a leak I micholi met Faye I guess
two and a half years ago yeah leading
the Stanford AI lab so she's a professor
of AI at Stanford and again runs the lab
there and then earlier this year joined
Google as their chief scientist of AI in
the Google cloud so welcome thank you
Mike so you know the the intent of you
give this discussion from my viewpoint
is like there's been a lot of I think
sometimes hype sometimes real and
advances around hey I NML and you know
from moving from the academic side and
starting to get exposure so you have a
place like Google you know on the
applied side of AML what is something
that's kind of surprised you like in
that transition that you're getting kind
of up to speed at Google that's a great
question like so this is I've been at
Google for two months and it's it's
actually the first time time I took a
deep dive into the industry and i am
very fortunate to have that sabbatical
opportunity so i think a couple things
that really surprised the but also
excites me and one thing is that as a
technologist I've been doing AI for
almost 20 years and you know in the
early days i started a i as an undergrad
and PhD student and then professor in
the early days this is such a nice small
academically driven problem it's an
intellectual pursuit and then gradually
we really this generation witness this
technology at least of this wave
maturing and making impact and solving
real-world problems so our dream of a i
started also to grow in that process and
I came to the realization in the past
few years that we're going to a lot of
people call the fourth Industrial
Revolution
and I have absolutely no doubt that AI
is one of the biggest driving force of
the Industrial Revolution were
automation and many things are changing
the way humans live and work but there
has always been a question for me right
around the time that I was considering
my sabbatical industry is how do we
democratize this technology so there
there are many reasons we want to
democratize first of all it's a good
thing a lot of it is a good thing we
want humanities to benefit from it
second is I think that I would not want
AI to be in the hands of a few
privileged and elite by democratizing it
has it helps us to really focus on a
benevolent effect of AI and this is
where cloud comes in it took me a while
but I start realized that cloud is the
biggest computing platform humanity has
ever created and and cloud what is
computing today computing is to make
your data speak intelligently and act
intelligently to solve your problem or
your customers problem so really the
marriage between AI and cloud is like
this perfect vehicle to democratize and
I do you think that in this fourth wave
as you flow as you're living in a
fantastically describe it is it being
driven then by compute by would say some
of these advances around within
convolutional neural nets and then is it
in is it also the tag label data or what
what are the kind of big factors that
have also resulted in a converted kind
of new yawk the very large noise or into
some signal which I'll talk about a bit
in the same I think you pointed out I
think the three major factors are the
computer in the hardware not only the
huge infrastructure that
cloud can provide but also the GPUs the
remaining advances in hard work then um
20 years ago internet brought us
gradually the big data movement and big
data and the availability of labeled and
annotated big data is the second factor
and then the third factor is advances of
the algorithms that is what I think
academia have been doing the past AI has
been the field of almost six six five to
six decades but in the past 20 years so
these three factors converged and
brought us today ai and cloud will be
the vehicle to democratize it another
thing so I'm not gonna have time
introduce myself so in general for a
client birkin yeah we see i see by the
MU 15 companies a week probably out of
the 15 call it 10 to 15 use the terms AI
ml and it's kind of disappointing at
times maybe it's disappoint I'm is a
majority those actually when you push on
their claims either don't really
understand what you're saying or I'm
really not using AI and another pair we
want your attention yeah so um cuz I and
unfortunately with a lot of money in the
ecosystem and so let me accompany the
public edge can invest in how do how do
we kind of get past that noise and we've
got so many founders entrepreneurs in
the audience that likely or in some
cases doing relay I'm al how happen from
your perspective immaculee how do we
going to get that signal above the noise
because it is kind of a noisy area right
now right i think there is a couple of
things especially you know you and I
have been working together in the
several ab entrepreneur club for
students and so I've been also learning
a lot from the the winter capital world
I think a couple of things I would tell
startup founders one is that still think
about your problem focus on the problem
focus on the problem you want to solve
is the entry going to everything think
about what products you want to deliver
to your problem and and and to your
customers to your users do too and once
you have that start thinking about the
data I think when you talk to a founder
CEO or CEO it's really important to see
if they have a good grasp of what data
they have and how do they how do they
use their data that is so important
that's the beginning of a IML you cannot
speak AM L in that vacuum can I can
interrupt your your listener on the data
size do you think that over time the
groups or companies that have the
largest corpus of tagged data is that
where the IP is going to really sit part
of it is that the companies with the big
data and paths are going to win part of
it but another hand there is so much
opportunity because these big companies
are not going to go deep into verticals
or specific areas there's still a lot of
opportunities or and also and also this
is where the the creativity of startup
comes in how do you snowball your data
you have to have a clever design of the
product and engagement with your
whatever consumer or Turner so that as
as you begin that process you you your
product you you design into the product
snowballing effect of data so that
that's not just data personally you can
not always assume that okay I start the
company with all this data and therefore
somehow excitable exactly yeah but you
have to have a pattern strategy yeah and
the other way otherwise every Cavill
competition with is very valuable
exactly right so that's one thing data
the other thing is I guess if a company
truly understand data truly understand
the value of data analytics then they
should invest in a good depending on the
on the product data scientist AI machine
learning
experts and that's where homework needs
to be done so let's push on that Allah
so she can attend everyone so I totally
agree with you I'm focusing on the
problem and unite you mentioned that you
know periodic member of the week
spending time with some of your grad
students on what are the opportunities
and applications and you know we have
this 117 spectrum we mentioned kind of
the noise and then we can have the other
side of section which is because the PhD
students or the first thing is finished
I can say this is the PhD drop out where
he or she feels like they've got a
hammer right and everything looks like a
nail right and so you can kind of how
and officially in this area when you're
building a company just want to solve
the problem you're not in love with the
algorithm or the approach how you hear
about how do you kind of give guidance
to the folk science around that as well
as how do you hire someone in the area
that and kind of mitigate this risk of
not just in love with a piece of paper
so I don't know Mike there is one
singular answer because sometimes that
tremendous hammer vision the technology
vision does drive crazy too long arc
that no one have seen the usage and we
should push on that technology I mean no
way Google started as a search engine
where the product vision was not yet
mature yet that technology drove that so
sometimes that those opportunities do
exists but also I agree with you that
many times technologists who want to go
solve a real-world problem have to
develop that empathetic understanding of
the problem and and and what you want to
deliver just stay staying at the thesis
dissertation paper level is not enough
it's really important to come come by
now with empathetic you know there's a
discipline to really force yourself to
be in reading about I think that's right
when you can look at the discussions
you're having with students that ain't a
witch get recruit a quick Google or for
the summit on of stress
car company there's a new startup what's
the guidance that you give your students
on how to either have that discussion
around a problem with the potential
customer or find a co-founder to that
because I they recognize the fact that
hey I'm a technologist I need to find a
product person or a business person
that's why I bring you guys to talk to
this person so I come to tell you them
said first of all I'm a professor that
first tell them go be a professor that's
my first but if they say no I absolutely
have to do a start-up as L can let me
help you I've good friends I can
introduce you to but I think it's really
about um I tell them take away the
romance it's when you're really dive
into a startup world as a technologist
try to take all the fluff of the romance
out and really get to the ground focus
on the technology on the problem and and
try to recognize that um you don't know
everything you know as a technologist
and seek guidance or mentorship or help
or partners that can complete that
picture for you to really at the end of
the day is about delivering what your
customer and users want it's not about
that one line of equation that is very
flashy so I promised you before hands of
that guy's cutie difficult but I mean
clearly your world I mean globally
recognized as a leader in a i had many
different opportunities i'm sure during
her sabbatical ago why google haha
thanks for asking yes that's a good
question i actually did take some time
to think about it i was fortunate enough
to have multiple opportunities i think
at the end of the day was what i just
said i want to democratize AI i really
believe this technology is so important
for the entire
manatee that we shouldn't keep it in the
hands of a few and when I think about
from an industry point of view how we
democratize AI we should really think
about all the important verticals today
that can benefit from AI in Silicon
Valley we tend to have a little bit of a
myopia or the skewed view about
industries about high-tech access
self-driving cars and social media but
really if you look at the world there is
finance health care education
manufacturing agriculture you know just
government there are so many vertical
sectors that would benefit from this
technology and if that well they arrive
at that conclusion I want the best
platform to democratize AI those are so
clear that cloud is the best Russell and
and Google is a company with the deepest
AI technology and the cloud so so I sure
would you use the vision and the
opportunity and excitement there one of
the kind of obvious implications there
may be a lot of displaced job
potentially as we go to some of these
how do you think about it how does I
mean with what you can comment from
google cloud how do we solve that
problem I mean in terms of we've got a
lot of displaced workers retrain or how
everything okay yeah so um I think
that's a really important topic and as
an AI person I I think we all have
responsibilities to to think beyond just
the technology or the codes but into the
social implication I want to have a
little crow to one fact when ATM
machines are introduced to the bank
which is a way to automate a lot of bank
tellers jobs right now you just go to
the Machine and do the basic thing the
number of colors in you US banks has
increased not decreased
that's a single small small example to
show when certain jobs are being
replaced by machines humans we have a
tendency to crave more different jobs to
make the service better to make the
product better to reach deeper into the
needs of consumers so today's bank
tellers do a lot of things that are a
little more fun higher level than just
processing checks and giving you the
cash so I think this is where we need to
be going collectively as a society I'm
not an economist and I'm not a policy
maker but we try to bring that voice to
the to the years of the policy makers is
that it is time to think about how a is
killing in backdrops you know the
drivers the the bank tellers the Queen
into the caravan killing of the
opportunities are creative officious
exactly here we need to proactively
start thinking about that my hunt is
that the world is this is a growing time
I guess I'm an optimist this is a
growing pie this is not a zero-sum game
and we need to be growing this pie
together so mom you know if I'm a
company in the audience and I had some
ideas around what AI or ml could
potentially do with my product and
impact my customer what what can I
guidance can you give from like helping
that means like either vet or recruit
those folks they can compete with your
current employer which a little bit
maybe put your position but it's a
question I get a lot it's like well I
need the data scientist ago I can't find
he or she or how I festa said I don't
have a PhD in the area yeah do your
homework I mean how is that so um there
are many things you know look at their
degrees look at what they have done look
at even if someone doesn't have a formal
machine learning or data science degree
there are so many online courses cago
the
there is you know developers forums look
at what they have done that github can
have they you know depending what kind
of talent you're looking for but if
you're looking for that machine learning
engineer you you need to do your due
diligence and see what they have
produced talk to your engineers talk to
your vc's talk to your mentors I think
at the end of the day it's about that
CEO or that co-founder or founder doing
his or her homework yeah i agree i
missed again one of the things that
unify folks when I should I talked with
other professors at Stanford is
periodically we see stories and larger
companies that have this really
interesting data set or corpus and they
can't hire these data scientists and the
same token on the academic side is
always a desired of like we find the
problems helps with grants etc etc what
are your thoughts on I can better
connect that that linkage of the private
sector and academia where there may be
people that want to go to the professor
but there is a incredible data set let's
say from this commerce company that may
have been hiring well first of all
consider clouds come to 12 yes there is
more and more startups and fortune 500
companies using the cloud is one of the
values we provide at Google Cloud is is
that we do the computing and solve some
of your problems for for you right like
not everybody has to be a ninja in
everything but they could drink a little
bit deeper side I agree on the compute
but when we start talking about feature
engineering and building models for a
unique problem I don't know if Google
will necessarily help with that actually
it does I mean I don't want to be just
Google eccentric but let me push back a
little bit you know if you look at some
of our the AI product we offer on the
cloud is exactly first of all deep
learning takes away feature engineering
that's part of the revolution of deep
learning machine learning that preceded
deep learning was takes more nuanced
expertise to 22 into the problem and you
really need to know how to do feature
engineering but deep learning you
make that a lot easier and better second
second is that cloud through the api's
and other you know at Google we even
have a lab that brings people into the
lab to to work with you handing hand to
look at your data formulate your problem
and solve the problem so there is a lot
of services we do provide into I think
collaboration this world is so connected
sometimes as I start of you need to or
company nothing put yankin is a sales
spot but I mean Microsoft has a pretty
rich offering measure and ml 2 so how do
I should I think about google versus max
that works I try both to see what works
best for me or so um I said earlier I
decided to go in Google as a I
technologist because Google has the best
AI technology and if you look at what
Google and alphabetically by their feet
so it makes a lot of sense yeah exactly
i did a little bit with my feet from
what google bring our deep mind rest of
Google research I think that deep
technology and today some of Google's
own products are running on Google's
deep learning technology I think that
speaks volume about that what a lot of
doctoring there yeah i know we're out of
time but ok thank you so much for
everything imagic it's phenomenal that
you're at Google working with diane and
can we can see what you and your team
built okay thank you
[Applause]
ok