what I want is set maybe high-level
vision sheriff view some some of the
ideas I think are the big ideas in
future learning and deep learning I
think the agenda of deep learning as the
idea of using brain simulations to make
learning albums my Brendan easy to use
and also make revolution advances in
machine learning nai so come back to
this later but you know once upon a time
I guess when I was in high school I
think I joined the field of machine
learning because I want to work on AI
but somehow that got lost and instead of
actually doing AI we wound up spending
our lives doing curve fitting which is
not what I signed up to do of and deep
learning was for the first time in many
years made me think about the bigger
dreams again I should come back and say
a bit more about that and again I won't
say you know the sort of vision and
ideas on a share is really not mine but
as I think shared by large community
including you know young Jeff Fintan
yoshua bengio many others that you hear
from in the next couple weeks what about
computers do without data right we want
to look at images and label them look of
audio listen to audio and do speech
recognition have text and do stuff will
text and it turns out that machine
learning is our best shot and most of
these applications today but it is very
difficult to get these applications work
right so while back I all some of my
students at Stanford to use like a
state-of-the-art computer vision
algorithms to to write the motorcycle
detector and this was the result be God
and this is typical in computer vision
right this is so um well even though
learning algorithms works each of those
lines is like a you know six months to
two years of work for a team of
engineers and and we light these
algorithms to be less work to build and
also maybe perform better so let me
start to explain some of these ideas
using computer vision but and then I
will talk a bit about audio and apply
these albums other modalities as well so
why is this problem hard right so
obviously a motorcycle how on earth
could the computer failed to recognize
what this is zooming into small part of
the image zooming into whether
little red square is where you and I see
a motorcycle the computer sees this so
the computer vision problem is to look
at all those pixel intensity values and
tell you that all those numbers
represent the exhaust pipe of a
motorcycle seems like you need a very
complicated function to do that and how
do we do this so machine learning you
know machine learning guys like me say
oh just feed the data to the learning
algorithm and let the learning algorithm
do this job right when I teach my
machine learning class I draw pictures
like this and this is just not how it
works oh so let's pick a couple pixels
and let's plot some examples right so
take that image there and because pixel
one is relatively dark and pixel to is
relatively bright that image you know it
has has that position in this figure now
let's take a different example a
different motorcycle image has a this is
a bright to pixel one and the darker
pixel too so that second image has
passed a different location and then
let's do this for a few negative
examples as well no motorcycles and what
you following is that if you plot a set
of positive and negative motorcycle and
not motorcycle images that you're
positive negative examples are extremely
jumbled together and so if you feed this
data to you know certainly a linear
classifier it doesn't work so what is
done is dead in machine learning is that
we won't want to be nice if you could
come up with what's called a feature
representation if you could write a
piece of code that tells you does this
image have handlebars in it does this
image have tires or wheels in it and if
you could do that then your data looks
more like this on the lower right and it
then becomes easy much easier for sale
linear classifier like so vector machine
with logistic regression to distinguish
the motorcycles from the banal motor
signals right but the story goes on so
will this in this illustrative example
or saying well whether we could write a
piece of code to tell us that their
handlebars and wheels but we don't
actually know how to do that and so in
computer vision what is done is actually
the following this is how people
actually come up with features in
computer vision this is kind of notional
illustrative example but this is what
I'm going to do when I take one well as
I go away I'm going to detect edges at
four different orientations so look for
vertical edges horizontal ages 45 degree
ages 135-degree ages and then what this
number 0 point 7 and the upper right
means right that number is saying that
the density of vertical edges in the
upper right-hand quadrant of my image is
0.7 and what and what this number down
here says is that the density of
horizontal edges you know in the lower
right-hand quadrant of my images 0 point
5 and in case you're getting the sense
that sort of like oh my god what on
earth is going on the air this seems
hardly complicated how it worked it will
come up with this piece of code you know
that's that's that's the point and sadly
this is the way the lot of computer
vision is done today so more probably
this notion of a feature representation
is pervasive throughout machine learning
in fact I guess I live in I live in
Silicon Valley and if you walk around
Silicon Valley and look at well where
people are spending all the engineering
time is often in coming up with these
feature representations so let's let's
look what's delve deeper right so where
do these features come from um since
they're the primary lens through which
our algorithms see the world this gives
them a certain important right so how
about computer vision oh and then in
facts are interesting and in fact this
notion of Peter representations is
pervasive you know for vision audio text
even other applications so what do you
get the features from in computer vision
the state-of-the-art answer for where
the features come from is that teams of
tens hundreds or teams of some of tens
hundreds or maybe thousands of computer
vision researchers have spent decades of
their lives hand engineering features
for computer vision
the finger on the upper left is a figure
that I took from the stiff paper thus if
paper is the single most highly cited
paper in computer vision like lost 15
years and I've read the paper maybe
about five times now and I still have no
idea what it's doing this is something
so complex piece of code that David
loads good friend David will tell you
this himself it took David literally ten
years I'm knocking he's he'll say ten
years himself of you know filling with
pieces of the code in order to come up
with the SIP feature which works pretty
well but you know you have to ask is
there a better way to design features
than this um that's vision how about
audio same thing right teams of tens
hundreds of thousands of audio
researchers working on features for
audio FCC is shown on the upper right
that's actually a pretty clever
surprisingly hard to beat but again you
know honestly to this day I have a hard
time understanding what some bits of the
mfcc album are doing and natural
language in fact I think most of natural
language processing text processing
today is unapologetically about finding
better features so think about pauses
right there's a lot of NLP work on
parsers um this piece of software that
tells you where the noun phrases are in
your sentence I mean why on earth do I
care where the noun phrases are in my
sentences I really don't need software
to tell me that the only reason we spend
so much time working on pauses is
because we hope that this will give us
useful features to then feed to some
later downstream application like
anti-spam web search machine translation
that we actually care about so common
features is difficult time-consuming
requires expert knowledge and we're
working with them applications machine
learning you know we spent a long time
there's a way if you look at apply
machine learning where they will walk a
new go the company local people doing
apply machine learning this is really
what they spend the vast majority of the
time on
is coming with features so can we do
better so the next piece in a lot of
deep learning there's a like many people
in very like many of you I tend to treat
biological inspiration with a great deal
of caution and an even a healthy dose of
skepticism but for me a lot of the sum
all of my thinking about deep learning
has been taken inspiration from biology
so only share of you you know some some
cool cool ideas from really by
Washington's variation so turns out
there's a fascinating hypothesis that
much of human intelligence can be
explained by a single learning algorithm
those calls the one learning our
hypothesis let me share with you some
evidence for this right so this one's
experiment first done on ferrets in MIT
um that great piece of brain tissue
shown on the slide that's your auditory
cortex the way that your understanding
my words now is that your ears is
routing the sound signal to that piece
of red brain tissue and this processing
of sound and then that's how you you
eventually get to understand what I'm
saying so neuro scientists did the
following experiments which is in cut
the wire between the ears and the
auditory cortex and do what's called a
new row rewiring experiment so that
eventually the signal from the eyes gets
routed to the auditory cortex then turns
out they we do this that red piece of
brain tissue she learns to see and this
is the word see this has been replicated
in multiple labs on four species of
animals and these animals can quote see
in every single sense of the word that I
know how to use the word see these
animals they can do visual
discrimination toss we can look at
things and make correct decisions based
on you know an image in front of them
using that rare piece of brain tissue
another example this rare piece of brain
tissue is your somatosensory cortex is
responsible for your sense of touch do a
similar neuro rewiring experiment and
your somatic concerns we call text Lucy
um so well generally this is idea that
if the same physical piece of brain
tissue right the same physical bit of
your brain can process sight or sound or
touch or maybe even other things then
maybe there is a single learning
algorithm they can process sight or
sound or touch or maybe other things and
that it can you know discover some
approximation to that learning algorithm
when we discover a totally different
algorithm but it accomplishes the same
thing then that might be a better way to
watch making progress in AI then hand
engineering separate pieces of code in
each of these individual application
silos which we have been doing for
decades now just a few more fun examples
it turns out you can plug in other
sensors to the brain and the brain kind
of figures out how to deal with it shown
on the upper left is a scene with your
tongue right so this is actually
undergoing FDA trials of now to help
blind people see a system called brain
port so the way it works is you strap a
camera as your forehead takes a low
resolution grayscale image of what's in
front of you run a wire to a rectangular
array of electrodes that you place on
top of you as a tongue so the each pixel
maps to a point on your tongue and maybe
a high voltage is a bright pixel and a
little voltage is a dark pixel and even
as adults you and I today would be able
to learn to see you about tongues in
like tens they all late n 3 10 20
minutes human echolocation well you need
to know snap your fingers great i'll
click your tongue and there are there
actually schools today training blind
children to learn to interpret the
pattern of sounds bouncing off the
environment as human sonar a haptic belt
is you know bring a buzzes around your
waist program the one facing north to
buzz and then you get the directions and
you just magically know where in office
similar to help birds sense direction
you can focal third i interferon and you
know the frog learns how to
it doesn't work in every single instance
there are cases where this doesn't work
but I think to a surprisingly large
extent it's almost as if you can plug in
you know not quite any sensor but almost
the large range of sensors on to almost
any part of the brain and kind of learn
to do of it so I want to be cool if we
get a learning algorithm to do the same
so let's see oh let's take a break could
you guys on I think you now know enough
to work look at the questions 1 through
3 in the handout do you guys want to
take a few minutes so just write down do
write down what you think is the right
answer and when you've done so you know
discuss what she wrote down with your
neighbors and and see if you agree or
disagree for a question one I had d for
question two I had auditory cortex
learns to see and to question three I
don't know different people have
different ideas I guess I i tend to use
the wording that much of human
intelligence can be explained by a
single learning algorithm but there are
lots of other Worthing's that lots of
other ways of describing it alright so
given this um you know what are the
implications for machine learning right
so here if we think that without visual
system computes an incredibly
complicated function of the input right
it looks all those numbers and those
pixel values and tells you that that's
the motorcycle exhaust pipe and so two
approaches that we could try to build
such a system as you could try to
directly implement this complicated
function which is what I think of as a
hand engineering approach or maybe you
can try to learn this function instead
right and in kind of a side comment
maybe only for the aficionados of
machine learning is that if you look at
a train learning algorithm you know a
learning algorithm after has trained
with all the parameter values there's a
very complex thing but the learning
algorithm itself is relatively simple
most learning algorithms
striving a half a page of pseudocode so
the complexity of the things we're
training usually comes from the
complexity of the data rather than the
complexity of the algorithm and then
that's a good thing because we know how
to get complex data you just here which
is an image is all around us but coming
up with complex algorithms is hard right
so here's a here's a problem that I
guess I post a few years ago which is
you know can we learn a better feature
representation for vision or audio or
what have you so completely can you come
up with an algorithm they just examine
examines a bunch of images like these
and automatically comes up with a better
way to represent images than the raw
pixels and if you can do that maybe you
can apply the same algorithm to audio
and have the same algorithm training
along a bunch of audio clips and have it
find a better way to represent audio
than the raw data okay so let's let's
write down the mathematical formalism of
this problem right which is given a 14 x
14 image x image patch x one way to
represent the image patch is with a list
of 196 roll numbers corresponding to the
pixel intensity values the problem one
opposes can we come up with a better
feature vector to represent those pixels
okay and if you can do so then this is
what you can do she has a problem called
a self-taught learning i guess which is
well so in traditional machine learning
right if you want to learn to
distinguish your motorcycles from non
motorcycles you have a training set with
some and this is a pain because there's
a lot of work to come up with a lot of
pictures and motorcycles it was like
tens of thousands of them so in the
unsupervised feature learning on the
cell for learning problem what you do is
instead we're going to give you a large
source of unlabeled images will give you
infinite source of unlabeled images
because of the web where we all have an
effectively infinite source of images
and the task is
can all those random images up there
somehow can pictures of trees and
sunsets and horses and so on can that
help you to do a better job figuring out
that this picture down here there's a
motorcycle okay and so one way to do
that is that we have an algorithm that
can look at these on label images and
learn a much better representation of
images than just the raw pixels and if
that superior representation allows us
to then look at a small label training
set and if this my superior
representation allows us to use the
small label training set just do a much
better job figuring out what this test
I'll images ok so i guess in machine
learning there are sort of three
standard three a few common formalisms
right there's the supervised learning
setting which is the oldest will
standard one that most you best know so
let's here goes the record distinguish
between cars and motorcycles right so in
the standard year old school like 50
year old supervised learning exciting 30
year old supervisor is I think you need
to come over a large training set up
above the cause a lot of all the cycles
okay um about 10-15 years ago deciding
Andrew McCollum Tom Mitchell or maybe
even others before them start to talk
about semi-supervised learning the idea
of using unlabeled data and that was
exciting but in semi-supervised learning
as is simply conceived um you know the
ability to use unlabeled data is great
but in semi supervised learning
typically the unlabeled data is all
images or causing motorcycles and it
turns out that this is a semi-supervised
learning this sort of model is not
widely used because it turns out that um
you know rarely do you have a data set
of where all the images are get it cause
all motorcycles and nothing else but the
only thing we're doing is just missing
the label so this is kind of useful but
isn't why they use whereas in them what
I call self alerting the goal is to take
you know totally random images that
maybe cause made motorcycles maybe toe
the other random things
and two can you can use somehow use this
to learn to distinguish the house and
motorcycles and one weight is why would
I like to think about it is that you
know the first time that a child sees a
new object someone invents a new vehicle
weight the first time that you and I saw
Segway we learn to recognize the Segway
very quickly just from seeing it once
and I think the reason that we learn to
recognize a Segway very quickly is
because you're in my visual system prior
to that had had several decades of
experience looking at random natural
images just seeing the world and was by
looking at these random unlabeled images
that allow us that allowed you in my
visual system to learn enough about the
structure of the world to come up with
better features if you will so that the
first time you saw a Segway you very
quickly learn to recognize what a Segway
is right so just to make sure you got
this concept could you please a look at
question before and just do that map
this to a new example all right so
someone called the answer well first
first part a PCOD second part and third
part all right also all right that was
easy cool so how do we actually do this
in order to come up with an algorithm to
learn features let's turn one last time
to biological motivation turns out that
when your brain gets an image the first
thing it does is look for edges in the
image rights so first stage of visual
processing on the brain is called visual
cortical air review one I think Jon
might have mentioned this yesterday and
the first thing it does is look for ages
or lines i'm going to use the term lines
and edges interchangeably so in your
brain right now there's probably a
neuron that is looking for a 45 degree
line 45 degree h like this shown on the
left with the dark region mix too bright
region and there's probably a different
neuron in your brain right now there's
looking for a vertical line like this
one right here okay so um how can we get
our software to maybe mimic the brain
and also find edges like this what we
don't want to do is code this up by hand
I what I don't want to do is tell the
neuroscientist and then you work really
hard to right hand engineer software the
replicas does I think what's most much
more interesting is we can have an
algorithm learn these things by itself
and that there is such an algorithm is
very old ones like a what 16 year old
was out now do 20 thousand a few called
sparse coding you talked about this a
bit yesterday did you write cool so
there we go for this very quickly even a
small scolding was obviously conceived
as like a theoretical neuroscience model
so you know Bruno's heusen will tell you
right he never envisioned that this
would be used as a machine learning
algorithm this is like a theoretical
neuroscience result used to try to
explain you know computations in the
brain or something like that right and
this is how the album works is an
unsupervised learning algorithm so the
way where else is repeated a set of em
images x 1 x 2 up to X M so each input
example is and let's say an N by n
matrix yo go like a 14 x 14 image patch
what's fast coding does is it learns the
dictionary of basis functions Phi 1 Phi
2 up to 5 K such that each of your
training images X subject to the
constraint that the AJ's are mostly zero
spots in and the way this is implemented
is on where they are l one constraint
we're both
you know minimize the sum of absolute
value terms on the only coefficients AJ
okay the sparsity penalty sir and so if
you do this then on well they I think
this is the only equation I have for
this first hour so I hope you enjoyed it
so same thing in pictures if you train
sports clothing on natural images every
single time you're on it they'll learn
the set of basis functions that look a
lot like the edge protectors that you
know we believe visual protocol error v1
is looking for and then given a test
example given a test image X right what
what what it will do is it will select
out let's say three all of my 64 basis
functions here and it will take that
test example and explain it or decompose
it into a linear combination of in this
case just three out of 64 of my basis
functions okay so speaking loosely this
album has quote invented edge detection
right the album was free to choose
absolutely any basis functions at once
but it shows but you know if you run it
every time it chooses to learn basis
functions that look like these edges and
what this decomposition says is that
this image x is 0.8 times H number 36
plus OH point 3 times H number 42 plus
0.5 times H number 63 okay so if you
will this is saying this is now T
composed the image in terms of what
edges appear in this image and this
gives a high-level more succinct more
compact representation of the image and
also probably a more useful one right
because it's more useful to know where
the edges are in the image that you know
where the pixels are moreover this gives
us a alternative way to represent the
image instead of representing the image
patch using a list of 196 pixel values
we can instead
using this vector of numbers a 1 through
a 64 these are the coefficients
multiplying it to the basis functions in
just a few more examples so the method
indentation attention those represent an
image in terms I just appear in it and
it turns out that a funeral scientists
have done that had to invent a chef have
done quantitative comparison between
sparse coding and 0 and visual cortical
area v1 and found that you know it's not
as by no means a perfect explanation of
visual to everyone but but it matches of
unknown so surprisingly well on not all
but on many dimensions so that's vision
how about other input modalities so this
is a slide that got from Evan Smith from
his PhD thesis work with Michael Ricky
so what Evan did was he applies false
coding to audio data and what I've shown
here is 20 basis functions learned by
sparse coding when trained on natural
sounds ok so this is a grid of 5 by 4
you know what 5 by 4 the lower audio
clips i guess audio basis functions so
this 20 basis functions learned by
sparse coding um what he did was he then
went to the cat or the tree system since
the biologists in Boston had been you
know using electro recordings to figure
out what early auditory processing and
the cat does and for you should these 20
things learned by his algorithm he found
the closest match in the biological data
and the closest matches are shown over
the in red ok so the same algorithm the
only one hand gives a you know decent
explanation for early visual processing
and all the other hand juice maybe a you
know by no means perfect but but the
reason we expect some explanation to
relieve it auditory processing as well
and it turns out you can do a similar
study on them or the somatosensory
processing as well this is work done by
Andrew cycle Stanford
where he collected touch data how do you
call it touch data right so the way that
dumb Andrew Andrew sacks did it was um
you know so we hold things of our hands
all the time when I'm holding this thing
but how do you how do you actually
collect data for how I'm holding it so
the way Andrew sacks did it was um he
took a glove oh and he took an object
and he sprayed talcum powder all over
the object and then when you take a
glove and you hope this object and then
you let go the pattern of talcum powder
you know on your glove tells you where
you came into contact with the object
and moreover the density of talcum
powder actually corresponds a little bit
to the to the pressure and and not sure
why he did this but dumb he then
actually found so so what type of
objects to people holder I all we don't
know so here collecting data you want to
be representative of what animals do so
fortunately it turns out that there were
two biologists that has spent about a
year on the of their lives sitting on
some Island watching monkeys and
carefully documenting every single way
that monkeys pick up different things so
thank God I'm up computer sciences right
and so Andrew sacks you know took that
distribution of data and he wearing his
glove picked up objects using the same
distribution of drawers as was
documented in these monkeys on an island
oh and that was his data I think that
story was pretty fun but totally
unnecessary oh but Carlos are usually
goes you know so training training on
data like this that turns out that you
learn basis functions using sparse
coding that are I should say by no means
a perfect match to one to what is known
to what is believed to happen in
somatosensory cortex but this may be a
surprisingly good match
dimensions right so that's fast coding
um and let me could you take could you
do a five and six on the handle so
what's the answer four five and six wait
what's wait once what is most actually
where was it for six again okay come on
all right be right all right cool let's
exert the right so the bases are the
same for every image but is the
coefficients they want to rake eight
other features for the specific image
okay um all right great
so that's sparse coding and it turns out
that on the different ways to implement
you know sparse coding and what what I
just talked about was maybe the the
original way by ourselves net view in
1986 there much food there there are
different ways now I think young mother
talked about encoded ecole architectures
I'll talk a bit more about that later
today but i think this intuition of
learning space features has been kind of
key for is one of the ideas i guess that
allows us to learn very useful because
even from unlabeled data come back to
this later as well there are there other
ways to do it if any of you are familiar
with ica actually how many of you have
heard of the ica independent components
out as I oh cool all of you awesome so
it turns out that there's a you know
deep mathematical relationship between
ica and sparse coding that the turns out
the two albums are doing something very
similar for me personally these days I
tend to use the ica version so sparse
coding rather than the version I just
talked about but later today also talk
about about sparse altering colors with
different ways of learning sparse
features we get to that later but so
what do you do instead of you know you
just described is you know one layer of
one of these sparse feature learning our
rooms may be sparse coding maybe as
possible to encode there may be a sparse
VPN on spots rbm and turns out what you
can do really building on a jet engines
work what you can do is recursively
apply this procedure where instead of
just going from pixels to images excuse
me pixels to edges you can recursively
apply this procedure and you know just
as you can group together pixels to form
agency in group together edges to form
combinations of edges and group together
combinations of edges to form higher
level features so let me show an example
that this is an example run by Hall
actually it's not a Michigan professor
but what ho laughter
she trained one layer of ooze expose DBN
and first layer you know Alfred mercy
group together pixels for mages another
level up learn significant edges to form
models of object parts right so does
this oh i should say this this was an
example of sparse coding train just on
pictures of faces so the entire dataset
was pictures of faces right and then i'm
requesting you apply this the next level
up and learn more complete models of
faces so let me make sure that this
visualization makes sense right um when
I have this little square here shown
here what this little red what does
little square means is that I have
learned a neuron in the first level that
is looking for a vertical edge like that
one okay going one level up and and and
I've shown all these rectangles the same
size but higher up features are actually
looking at bigger regions of the image
okay it's just a resize all look the
same but one level up this is actually
looking at the bigger vision of the
image but one level up you know this
rectangle here means that at that next
level one of the neurons has learned to
detect eyes that look like that great
and then at the highest level you know
if you look at the upper left most
square say with that visualization is
showing that there's a neuron that has
learned to detect faces that you look
look a bit like that person okay if you
train the same algorithm on different
object classes you end up with different
decompositions of different object
classes into different object parts then
more complete models of objects if you
train the algorithm on a mix of four
different classes of objects so there's
an algorithm trained on a data set that
includes cause faces bikes and airplanes
then you know you end up with at the
mid-level you get features that shared
among the different object classes where
I don't know maybe what I guess are we
caused a motor bike expo 5th wheel tire
like shapes or your features that kind
of share between multiple parts and then
the highest level you get object
specific features
okay yeah I see yes there is there's a
point so because of the nature of the
visualization I showed them as though
images but yeah it if there's some
amounts of Indians that's hard to
visualize it oh I remember i have a
better example later today / where we're
more carefully document the invariant
zones have a better example later okay
so was this good for um when you went
when you hear your research isn't deep
learning like me talk you you see people
like y'all in me and geoff hinton is how
long stories I'd use but you know so you
can learn features so what is it good
for well turns out the Hollywood to
benchmark will stand the benchmark in
computer vision where the task is to
wash a short video clip and decide
whether you know any of a small number
of activities took place in this video
you know whether two people kids to do
hugs almost driving so as eating
someone's running the Badger activities
like the theater computer vision has
tried out many different combinations
that features last year hopefully soon
as standard found that by learning
rather than hand engineer the features
he was able to significantly outperform
the previous day we are all right how
about audio it turns out you can apply
similar ideas to audio so this is a
spectrogram which is a different
representation for audio you can take
slices of spectrograms and apply sparse
coding to that it turns out we do this
then on this is a dictionary of basis
functions learning for speech i guess
i'm not an excellent speech but in
impervia probably a slightly optimistic
as a
reading of these you know the basis
functions learn by sparse coding
correspond roughly to phonemes is a
slightly optimistic interpretation i
should say and so but if under this
slightly optimistic interpretation when
say informally that sparse coding has
learned to decompose speech data you
know very loosely into it because the
phonemes to the pier in speech and
moreover you can take this recursively
apply this idea just as we saw earlier
to build higher and higher level
features and i guess a few years ago oh
how likely so against the timid
benchmark is a data said that many
speech researchers work on this is one
of those data sets where you know if you
do point one percent better you write a
paper and a few years ago homeland was
able to you know make what correspondent
so I think worked out something like
like two-thirds of a decade word for
progress or something on this data set I
just might learn even this chart is
outdated i made this child i think back
when pauillac was publishing this paper
since publishing this paper geoff hinton
and others have surpassed is also using
deep learning techniques right um and
then as referring as was preparing this
talk i better for practice I ask my
students to help me put together a chart
of the sorcerer results where you know
we or others or whatever holders through
the odd benchmark result using deep
learning and there were surprisingly
many of them from us Stanford from other
groups
I've I say yeah I worked a machine
learning for a long time I've never in
my life seen anyone technology not go
over benchmarks like this quickly is
this the whole view the deep learning is
like knocking over benchmark like
nobody's business um there's actually a
lot more than fits on one slide I think
if I put all the ones I'm aware of it be
about three slides like this right
what's left to be done right so and I
know that some of you are you know here
because uh you want to learn how to
apply these things and I know some of
you are here because you might be even
interested in doing research yourselves
and writing research papers yourselves
in deep learning and future learning so
I want to share of you I'll do this
later to talk more about this later
there as well share of you what I think
of as a as a good way as one as one of
many promising directions in which to
you know take research for for deep
learning I think that's a scaling up so
I'm happy have we build effective deep
learning algorithms right how do we get
these animals work well well in fact how
do you build effective machine learning
algorithms you know so let's not back in
history right about 20 years ago oh
there were east debates about you know
where these different supervised
learning algorithms so no feature
learning yourself alone neighbors will
be supervised learning algorithms and
they use be all these debates about you
know is this new album better is my
album better so um Michelle banco and
eric bro did one of the studies that
most influenced my thinking where they
took maybe four of the city of the art
learning algorithms of the day I guess
back in 2001's ians were not yet popular
so they didn't actually study SVM's but
they took a natural language processing
costs on which they had a effectively
unlimited source of labeled data and
they train for learning algorithms and
plotted on the x-axis is a training set
size parts on the y-axis is the
performance is the accuracy all the
algorithms do about the same is the
amount of data you have and even a quote
soup
your algorithm will often lose to a
quote inferior algorithm if only you can
give the inferior alpha more data to
train on yeah so I think this results
like these that has led to this Maxim in
machine learning that you know says that
often is not who has the best algorithm
that witnesses who has the most data and
then I definitely see this over and over
and sleep and value of you if you look
at think about the most commercially
successful websites you know the ones
making large amounts of money in that
you Jews pray every day many of those
algorithms are incredibly simple is this
like logistic regression but the secret
is that those albums will fit far more
data than anyone else has so how about
so this is supervised learning um how
about unsupervised learning so Adam
coats as you who helped prepare this
handout a few years ago actually a year
and a half ago did this interesting
study right where he took all of the
unsupervised feature learning algorithms
of the day that you know that various
guys like us I guess debate is my averin
better as your offer better weather and
he took a bunch of these algorithms and
ran all of them and they read the model
size so for unsupervised feature
learning all of us have a have a large
amount of data right if you know you're
doing if you're learning from unlabeled
images from natural riches um you have
an infinite amount of data right news
and so the parameters the very is not
the amount of data is the size of the
models of how many features do you learn
those coefficients a1 just in the early
example we had 64 coefficients a1
through a 64 for sparse coding but let's
set that bigger let's learn a thousand
features instead or 10,000 whatever
let's learn much larger number features
and what Adam found was that you know
the album does matter maybe it matters
more than know maybe matt is more than
we respond supervised learning because
these albums are less mature but they
can be sold the silver is out where the
bigger the model the better it does and
in fact one interesting historical side
so C 4 10 we actually went back and
historically traced out you know I mean
we like to publish paper and say my
Oberon's better than yours yours valen
whatever right went back and traced all
the sequence of papers with you know
person a published as a result one CFR
person be published paper saying oh I
did better then person C published in LP
say I do even better and then the one
says oh I do even better in the idea
where we traced them a couple sequences
of that of supposedly benchmarks
advances in benchmark that was
supposedly do 20 miles better than yours
as I do better and we believe that a lot
of those results of the supposed
progress was actually because the models
got bigger right it's not that my
algorithm is actually better is it just
our most law had more time to work and
so I trained my better and so i'm going
to write a paper saying my ovens better
in the stuff I've done the one most
reliable way to get better results has
been to train a bigger model if I change
the algorithm sometimes it makes it
better sometimes not but in fact do I
you know look at the literature I feel
like a lot of work by a lot of different
research groups has been in some ways on
on trying to get these models to just
train bigger right so in this world of a
supervised future learning where all of
us have an infinite amount of data you
know I feel like we're not limited by
what data we have we're much more
limited by our ability to process the
infinite amount of data that all of us
have all right so you know many attempts
to come more efficient algorithms
parallelization I say yawns done very
cool work on the FPGA and a sec
implementation oh i think i bought i'm
going to take credit for bringing GPUs
to the deep learning world
um and and and so on a solid work like
this um and in fact looking at this
chart my personal interpretation which
others will disagree with is that those
results were achieved to a very large
part because of scalability issues right
but this is my personal interpretation
which others may disagree with could you
through the questions seven and eight on
the handout so question seven whether
you have which which ones did you check
off two and three cool I'll take your
word for it and for question 80 and I
just do actually questioning I can't
talk everything except DNA computing
them that's my answer anyway yeah I
thought of putting quantum in there too
but I think someone actually is working
on quantum computer yes yeah alright
cool so um let's see you know what
there's something else I could talk
about I think I'll do that towards the
end um so you know just to wrap up this
piece I think talk about the high-level
vision of less learning rather than
manually designing our features but
again kind of for me you know this isn't
just about machine learning anymore this
is I feel like um can we really learn
something about AI especially perceptual
ai ai ai and human intelligence is very
broad i think you know we're we're
starting to get a handle maybe the
perceptual part of AI which is maybe
like you know forty to sixty percent of
many animal brains right so this big
part of the brain and so what I'd like
to do is as I say you know thank you for
your attention for your patience with me
to do these things I hope that was
somewhat fun what like to do is let's
break and later on in the in the next
couple sessions where you know dive
slightly deeper into technical details
go from the basics talk about neural
networks and builders of the algorithms
also to the point out that you know
after you later today or whatever if you
want to go
deeper highly technical tutorial with
exercises in everything there's one up
there this is the URL was also given at
the bottom left of the handout but you
can you can check that out later after
today
you